<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Baziliōlogia a booke of kings beeing the true and liuely effigies of all our English kings from the Conquest vntill this present: with their seuerall coats of: armes, impreses and devises: and a briefe chronologie of their liues and deaths. Elegantly grauen in copper.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1618</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 13 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 28 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A03458</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 13581</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S106755</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99842465</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99842465</idno>
            <idno type="VID">7119</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A03458)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 7119)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1352:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Baziliōlogia a booke of kings beeing the true and liuely effigies of all our English kings from the Conquest vntill this present: with their seuerall coats of: armes, impreses and devises: and a briefe chronologie of their liues and deaths. Elegantly grauen in copper.</title>
                  <author>Elstracke, Renold, fl. 1590-1630, engraver.</author>
                  <author>Holland, Henry, 1583-1650?</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[27] leaves   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for H: Holland, and are to be sold by Comp: Holland ouer against th'exchange,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1618.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Engraved throughout.</note>
                  <note>The first "o" in "Baziliōlogia" is a Greek omega.</note>
                  <note>The foliation is conjectural, as copies were often Grangerized. For details of contents and states see Hind, Arthur M. Engraving in England, vol. 2, p. 115-139.</note>
                  <note>The plates are engraved by Renold Elstracke and others.</note>
                  <note>Twenty-three of these plates were also used in "The historie and lives, of the kings of England" by William Martyn (STC 17528-9).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  Kings and rulers --  Pictorial works --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-10</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="engraved_title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:7119:1"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <figure>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">IACOBUS D. G<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> MAG<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> FRAN: ET HI<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </q>
                     <figDesc>depiction of James I (James VI of Scotland) king of England</figDesc>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">ANNA D. G. MAG: BRITANNIAE<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> FRANCIAE<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ET HIBER REGINA</q>
                     <figDesc>depiction of Anne, queen consort of James I (James VI of Scotland) king of England</figDesc>
                  </figure>
                  <p>BAZILIωLOGIA A Booke of Kings Beeing<lb/> The true and liuely EFFIGIES of all our Engliſh Kings from the Conqueſt vntill this preſent: with their ſeuerall Coats of: Armes, Jmpreſes and Deviſes<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> And a briefe Chronologie of their liues and deaths.</p>
                  <p>Elegantly grauen in Copper.</p>
                  <p>Printed for H: Holland, and are to be ſold by Comp: Holland ouer againſt th'exchange 1618</p>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="catalogue_of_the_post-Conquest_rulers_of_Britain">
            <div n="William I" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:2"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>WILHELMVS CONQUESTOR REX ANGLIAE, DUX NORMANNORUM. ET<hi rend="sup">c</hi>.</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of William I (William the Conqueror) king of England</figDesc>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">Fortiter reſiſtendum</q>
                     <p>William the Conqueror Duke of Normandy (after he had in Battaile slaine Harolde) toke vppon him the Crowne of England. He raigned 19 yeares, 11 monthes<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> died at the age of 74 yeares, and lieth buried at Caen in Normandy. Anno 1087.</p>
                     <byline>R: Elſtracke ſculpſit</byline>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt th'exchang<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="William II" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:3"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>WILHELMUS II REX ANGLIAE ET DUX NOR<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>MANNIAE. ETc:</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of William Rufus (William II of England)</figDesc>
                     <p>William Rufus King of England and Duke of Normandy: He was ſlaine being ſhot into the body by misfortune in new Foreſt in Hamſhire, after he had raigned 12 yeares and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> monthes, at the age of 43, and lieth buried at Wincheſter Anno <hi>1100.</hi>
                     </p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland our againgt th'exchange</p>
                     <byline>R.E. ſculp:</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry I" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>HENRICUS PRIMUS. REX ANGLIAE. ET NORMANNIAE DUX. ET<hi rend="sup">c</hi>
                     </head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry I of England</figDesc>
                     <p>HENRY the firſt (ſurnamed Beau-clark) King of Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land and Duke of Normandie: He raigned 35 yeares and 4 monthes died the 2 of December 1185. at the age of 67 yeares. and lieth buried at Reading. 1135.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt thexchange</p>
                     <byline>R E. ſculpſit</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Stephen" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>STEPHANUS REX ANGLIAE COMES BONONIAE ET MORTANIAE. &amp;c.</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Stephen (of Blois) king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>Stephen a Valiant Prince, ſonne to Stephen Earle of Blois, Charters, and Champaigne: and of Adela daughter to William <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Conquerour Vſurped the Kingdome of England, which caused him to be vexed with continuall warres. He raigned 18 yeares, 11 months and at the age of 49 yeares, and lieth buried at Feversham. 1154.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold b<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> C<gap reason="illegible" extent="6 letters">
                           <desc>••••••</desc>
                        </gap> Holland ov<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> a<gap reason="illegible" extent="6 letters">
                           <desc>••••••</desc>
                        </gap> the Exchang<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry II" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:7"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>HENRICUS II ANGLIAE REX: DUX NORMANIAE ET AQVITANAN<hi rend="sup">IAE</hi>: CO: PICTAV<hi rend="sup">IAE</hi> ET ANDIGAV<hi rend="sup">I•</hi> Dꝰ. HIBERNI<hi rend="sup">AE</hi>.</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry II, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>Henry the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> ſurnamed Shortmantle King of England, Duke of Normandy, and Aquitaine. Earle of Poicteres, and Anjov: Lord of Ireland. He raigned 34 yeares 9 months. died the 6<hi rend="sup">th.</hi> of July 1189 at the age of 61 yeares, and lieth buried at Fonteverard in Normandy.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt the Exchange.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Richard I" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:8"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>RICH<hi rend="sup">ARDꝰ</hi>. I. REX ANG: ET HIERUS: DUX NORMAN<hi rend="sup">IAE</hi>, CO: PICTAV<hi rend="sup">IAE</hi> / Dꝰ. HIBERNIAE.</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Richard I (the Lionhearted) king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The right Valiant Prince RICHARD ſurnamed Coeur-de-lion King of England and Hieruſalem, Duke of Normandy and Aquitane, Earle of Poiters and Aniou, Lo: of Ireland. &amp;c. He died at the age of 43 yeares An<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. 1199. after he had raigned 9 yeares, 9 months, and 22 dayes, and lieth buried at Fonteverard in Normandy.</p>
                     <p>A<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> to be ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> by Co<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 words">
                           <desc>〈◊◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> th'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>x<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                           <desc>••••</desc>
                        </gap>g<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="John" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:9" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>IOHANNES REX ANGLIAE, DVX NORMANNIAE, COMES PICTAVIAE ET ANDEGAVIAE Dꝰ HIB:</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of John (John Lackland) king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>IOHN King of England, Duke of Normandy and Aqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taine Earle of Poytou and Anjou, Lord of Jreland: He died at the age of 52 yeeres after he had reigned aboue 17 yeeres and lieth buried at Worceſter. 1216.</p>
                     <byline>R E: ſculpſit</byline>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt thexchange</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry III" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:10" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>HENRICUS III ANGLIAE REX. D: AQVITAN: C: PICTAVIAE ET ANDIGAVIAE. D<hi rend="sup">O</hi>. HIB:</head>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">DULCE BELLVM INEXP<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>TIS</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry III, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>HENRY the III. King of England: Duke of Aquitane. Earle of Poictiers and Anjou. Lord of Ireland. He died at the age of 65 yeares, after he had raigned 56 yeares and lieth intombed at Westminſter. 1272.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt the'xchange</p>
                     <byline>R: Elſtrack Sc</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Edward I" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:11"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>EDWARD<hi rend="sup">US</hi> PRIM<hi rend="sup">US</hi> ANGLIAE REX / DUX AQUITA<hi rend="sup">NI•</hi> CO: PICTAUIAE ET ANDIGAVIAE: D<hi rend="sup">Nꝰ</hi>. HIBERNIAE</head>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">HINC FORTIOR IBO</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Edward I (Edward Longshanks) king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The noble and Victorious Prince EDWARD the first ſurnamed Long-shanks) King of England, Duke of Aquitaine, Earle of Poictiers, and Anjou: Lo: of Jreland &amp;c. He Conquered Scotland, and brought from thence the Marble Chaire. He ſubdued and overcame Hewelyn Prince of Wales, and made his ſonne Edward Prince thereof. he died at the age of 68 yeares. 1307<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> after he had raigned 34 yeares 8 monthes. buried at Westminister.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Edward II" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:12"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>EDVARDUS SECUNDꝰ REX ANGLIAE DUX AQUITA<hi rend="sup">NIAE</hi> COMES PICTAV<hi rend="sup">IAE</hi> ANDIGAV<hi rend="sup">IAE</hi> ET PONTIEU / Dꝰ. HIBERN<hi rend="sup">IAE</hi>
                     </head>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">ARD<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                           <desc>…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Edward II, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>Edward the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. King of England Duke of Aquitaine Earle of Poictou, Anjou, and Pontieu, Lord of Ireland. He raigned 19. yeares. 7 moths: and was depoſed the 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Ianuary 1327. and ſhortly com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to priſon in Barkley Castle, and there cruelly murdered at the age of 43 yeares. buried at Glocester.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt the Exchange</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Edward III" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:13" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>EDWARDVS III. D. G. ANGLIAE ET FRANCIAE REX<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> DOMINUS HIBERNIAE.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">SAPIENTIA FORTVNAM</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Edward III, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The true pourtraicture of EDWARD III<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> borne at Windſore, of the age of 15 yeres was crowned at Weſtminster the 2 of Februarie 1326. he tooke the tittle of King of France<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> as dew vnto him, both by Ciuill Lawe<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and order of ſucceſſion: being the Nephew and next heir male of K: Charles IIII. his mothers brother<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> in regard wherof he quartred the armes of France with Englands. He raigned 50. yeres. 5. mo: He died at the manor of Shene in Surrey. Ano. 1377. buried in Weſtminſter.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt the'xchange</p>
                     <byline>R. E. ſculpſit.</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Richard II" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:14" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>RICHARDUS II ANGLIAE ET FRANCIAE REX, DOMINUS HIBERNIAE, ET<hi rend="sup">C</hi>.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HO<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> SO<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> QVI <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> Y <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Richard II, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The true pourtraicture of Richard the 2. King of England, and France, Lord of Jreland, and Prince of Cheſter he raigned 22 yeres, was depoſed and murther'd at Pomfraict Caſt: at the age of 33 yeares. Buried Firſt at Langley. and 14 yeares after by K Henry the 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> remoued to Weſtminſter, and their was honourably interred.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt the Exchange.</p>
                     <byline>R E. ſculp:</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry IV" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:15"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>HENRICUS QUARTUS ANGLIAE ET FRANCIAE REX / DOMINUS HIBERNIAE. &amp;c.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI M<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> Y PENSE</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry IV, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The right noble Prince Henry the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. King of England and Fraunce<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Lord of Ireland. &amp;c. Who died at the age of 46 yeares. in Anno. 1413. after he had raigned 13 yeares. 6 moneths, and 4 dayes, and lieth buried at Canterbury.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Comp: Holland ouer againſt the Exhange.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry V" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:16"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>HENRICVS V. ANGLIAE ET FRANCIAE REX. DOMINUS. HIBERNIAE.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI S<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">VNE SANS PLUS</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry V, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>HENRY the v. began his reigne, the 20 of March, and was crowned at Weſtminster the 9, of Aprill following 1413. He reigned gloriouſly 9 yeres, 5 monthes, he died in the Caſtle of Boys Vincent by Paris, the 1, of September, 1422. and lieth intombed in the Abbey of S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Peters at Weſtminster being of the age of 36 yeares when he departed this world</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt th'exchange</p>
                     <byline>R E. ſculp:</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry VI" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:17"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>HENRICVS VI. D. G. ANGLIAE ET FRANCIAE REX. DOMINUS HIBERNIAE ETc</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> MAL Y PENSE</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry VI, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>HENRY the VI borne at Windſor being of the age of eight Monthes beganne his reigne the 31 of Auguſt 1422. and crowned King of England at Weſtminſter, the 6 of Nouember. 1429. and of Fraunce the 7 of December 1432. he reigned 38 yeres, 6 monthes, he died by violence, May 21. aged 52. An<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>o 1471. firſt buried at Chertſey Abbey, thence remoued to Windſore, wher he was ſolempley inter'd.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt the Exchange.</p>
                     <byline>R E. ſculpſit</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Edward IV" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:18"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>EDWARDUS IIII. ANGLIAE ET FRANCIAE REX DOMINꝰHIBER</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOI<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> MAL Y PENSE</q>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">HIC HAEC HOC TACEATIS</q>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">EXPIABIT AVT OBRVET</q>
                     <figDesc>Edward IV, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The right n<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap>e Prince <hi>EDWARD</hi> the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> King of England and Fraunce Lord of Ireland. He raigned 22 yeares and 5 weekes. Died at the age of 52 y<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ares: buried at Windſor. 1483.</p>
                     <byline>R. Elſtra<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ke ſculpſit</byline>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt th'exchange</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Richard III" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:19"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>RICHARDUS TERTIVS ANGLIAE ET FRANCIAE REX / DOMINVS HYBERNIAE. etc.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ONI SOIT <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>L Y PENSE</q>
                     <p>The portraict of RICHARD the 3. King of England, and Fraunce, Lord of Ireland. He was ſlaine at Boſworth feild the 22<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. of August 1486. and homelye buried at the Graye friers Church in Leicester, when he had vſurped 2 yeares 2 monthes and one day</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt the Exchange.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Edward V" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:20" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>EDVARDVS QVINTVS ANGLIAE ET GALLIAE REX / DOMINVS HYBERNIAE. etc.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>AL Y PENSE</q>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">BREVIS VIT<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> LEVIS CVLPA</q>
                     <p>The picture of Edward the 5. who at the age of 13 yeares was depoſed and cruelly murdered, by the procurement of Richard Duke of Gloucester his vnnaturall vnkle, when he had raigned 2 moneths and 11. dayes. and obſcurely buried in the Tower. 1183.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſould by Compton Holland ouer againſt the Exchange.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry VII" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:21" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>PRUDENTISS: PRIN: HENRICUS VII. D. G. ANGLIAE / GALLIAE HIBERNIAE REX. &amp;c.</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry VII, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The most Mighty and Prudent Prince Henry the ſeaventh by the grace of god King of England Fraunce and Ireland &amp;c.</p>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Com: Holland over againſt the Exchange.</p>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Henry VIII" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:22" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>UERA EFFIGIES HENRICI .VIII. ANGLIAE FRANCIAE, ET HIBERNIAE REX FIDEI DEFENS<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> MAL Y PENSE</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Henry VIII, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The mighty and moſt magnificent Prince, Henry the eight, king of England, Fraunce, and Ireland, defender of the faith, &amp;c. He raigned 37. yeares, and 10 monthes, died at the age of 57. yeares. &amp; lieth buriet at Windſo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </p>
                     <byline>Francisco Delaram Scu<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                           <desc>…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </byline>
                     <p>Are to be ſould by Io: Sudbu: &amp; G: Hu<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                           <desc>…</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Anne Boleyn" type="queen_consort">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:23"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>ANNA BOLOENIA HENRICI VIII ANGLIAE FRANCIAE ET HIBERNIAE REGIS CONIUX &amp;c</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Anne Boleyn, queen consort of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The Most Excellent Princeſse Anne Boleyn wife to King Henry the VIII. and mother to the moſt renowmed Queene Elizabeth of famous memorie of Englande<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> France and Irelande Queene. She departed this lyffe in the yeare of our Lord God .1535.</p>
                     <byline>R Elſtrack ſculpſit</byline>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by Compton Holland ouer againſt th'exchange</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Edward VI" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:24" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>EDWARDUS SEXTUS DEI GRATIA ANGLIAE / FRANCIAE ET HYBERNIAE REX. ETc.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT Q<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>AL Y PEN<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>E</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Edward VI, king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The true portraicture of King EDWARD the 6th. with the prayer that hee made to himſelfe, his eyes being cloſed, thinking none had heard him, 3 howers before his death, in the 7th yeare of his Raygne, and 16th. of his age. y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> 6 of Iul. A<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 1553.</p>
                     <p>
                        <q>LORD GOD deliuer me out of this miſerable and wreched life, and take mee amonge thy Choſen: howbeit not my will, but thy will be donne. Lord I commit my ſpirit to thee. Oh Lorde thou knoweſt howe happye it were for me to be with thee: yet for thy Choſens ſake ſend me life and health, that I may trulye ſerue thee. Oh my Lord God bleſse thy people and ſave thyne Inheritaunce. Oh Lord God ſave thy Choſen people of England. Oh my Lord God defend this Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alme from papiſtrye, and maynetayne thy true Religion, that I and my people may prayſe thy holy name.</q> Witneſse heerof <g ref="char:abpre">p̄</g>ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t were S<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Th: Wrath, S<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. H<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. Sidney, <hi>2</hi> of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Cheefe gentl: of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> pr<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>uie Chamber, Doct: Owen, Doct: Wendye, Chriſtop: Salmon groome.</p>
                     <byline>Si. Paſsaeus ſculp: L.</byline>
                     <p>Are to be ſould by
<list>
                           <item>Ioh: Sudbury &amp;</item>
                           <item>Geo: Humble</item>
                        </list>
                     </p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Mary I" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:25"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>UERA EFFIGIES<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> MARIAE<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> D. G. ANGLIAE, FRANCIAE, ET HIBERNIAE, REGINAE</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Mary I, queen of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The mighti<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Princeſs MARIE by The Grace of God Queene of England France and Ireland, &amp;c.</p>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONY SOIT <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> MAL Y PENSE</q>
                     <byline>Fran: Delaram Sculp.</byline>
                     <byline>Compton Holland excud:</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Elizabeth I" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:26"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>ELIZABETHA D. G. ANGLIAE, FRANCIAE, ET HIBERNIAE REGINA. MORTUA 1602.</head>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="6 words">
                           <desc>〈◊◊◊◊◊◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </q>
                     <q xml:lang="lat">
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap>P<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>R EADEM</q>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Elizabeth I, queen of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The moſt Excellent Princes of (Famous Memorie) ELIZABETH by the Grace of God Queene of England, France, and Ireland. Defendor of the Faith. &amp;c.</p>
                     <p>This Maiden-Queene Elizabeth, came into this world, the Eue of the Natiuitie of the bleſsed virgin Mary: and died on the Eue of the Annunciation of the virgin Mary 1602.</p>
                     <lg>
                        <l>* Shee was Shee is (what can there more be ſaid)?</l>
                        <l>In earth the first, in heauen the ſecond Maide</l>
                     </lg>
                     <p>Are to be ſold by I Su<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                           <desc>••••</desc>
                        </gap>y &amp; Ge<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                           <desc>…</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </p>
                     <byline>R Elstrak ſculpſit</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="James I" type="ruler">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:27"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>POTENTISS: IACOBUS D. G. MAGNAE BRITANNIAE, GALLIAE ET HIBERNIAE REX / FIDEI DEFENSOR</head>
                     <figDesc>portrait of James I (James VI of Scotland) king of England</figDesc>
                     <p>The right high and most mightie Monarch IAMES by the Grace of God King of great Britaine Fraunce and Ireland &amp;c Defendor of the Faith.</p>
                     <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>VI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                     <byline>Simon Paſsaeus delin: et ſculp:</byline>
                     <byline>Compton Holland excudit.</byline>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Anne" type="queen_consort">
               <pb facs="tcp:7119:28" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>
                  <figure>
                     <head>ANNA DEI GRA<gap reason="illegible" extent="4 letters">
                           <desc>••••</desc>
                        </gap> BRITANN<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                           <desc>•••</desc>
                        </gap> FRANCIAE ET HYB<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap>NIAE REGINA ETc.</head>
                     <q>LA MIA GRANDEZ<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> 
                        <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>L EXCELSO</q>
                     <p>Anno 1617</p>
                     <figDesc>portrait of Anne of Denmark, queen consort of James I of England</figDesc>
                     <q>
                        <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                           <body>
                              <div type="poem">
                                 <l>For FACE, for RACE, for GRACE, for euery thinge</l>
                                 <l>Which makes a SPOUSE fitt for a ROIALL KINGE</l>
                                 <l>Loe heere th Effigies which doth repreſent</l>
                                 <l>That PEERE, that SPOUSE, that IEMM most excellent</l>
                                 <l>Whom by a SACRED number I prove can</l>
                                 <l>A threefolde QVEENE, a threefolde CHRISTI-ANNE</l>
                                 <l>And by vniting THREE againe to ONE</l>
                                 <l>I maye affirme SHEE'S paraleld by none</l>
                                 <l>But is the EMPRESSE of true MAIESTIE</l>
                                 <l>Whom (GOD preſerue) nowe and Eternally.</l>
                                 <closer>
                                    <signed>HEN: FAR:</signed>
                                 </closer>
                              </div>
                           </body>
                        </floatingText>
                     </q>
                     <byline>Simon Paſsaeus ſculpsit Lond:</byline>
                     <p>Are to be ſould in Popes head Ally by Ioh Sudbury and Georg Humble.</p>
                  </figure>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
